Mobile: (+62) 81210155304

CUT **OLDA** LAVIANA

Email:cut.olda@gmail.com

Address: Kuta IV Blok D5 No. 11, Depok, West Java



PROFILE

26 years old Bachelor's graduate from Environmental Engineering Major of University of Indonesia who have worked as Environmental Staff for almost three years. Recently, I was worked at one of Panasonic Asia Group manufacture. Critical thinking, good at analysing, and also hard working had led me to awarded as student with outstanding achievements in Environmental Engineering major. My career objectives are to build long term career and give my best contributions to the company.

EDUCATION

University of Indonesia | Environmental Engineering (Bachelor) with GPA 3.49 / 4.00

JUL 2013 - JUL 2017

Major: AMDAL, Occupational HSE, Waste Water Engineering, Solid Waste Management, Hazardous Waste Treatment, Remediation of Contaminated Soil, Pollution Prevention, Air Pollution and Emission Control.

WORKING EXPERIENCES

PANASONIC INDUSTRIAL COMPONENTS INDONESIA MM2100 FACTORY | HSE OFFICER

SEP 2019 - JUN 2021

Main Responsibilities

- Responsible to implement the Environmental Management System based on ISO 14001:2015 and Occupational Health and Safety based on ISO 45001:2018
 - Identify environment issues in the company to determine the action plan.
 - Make environmental management program related to energy, water, waste, and chemical substances reduction.
 - Asses the aspect that impact to the environment and eliminate the significant impact.
 - Evaluate the environmental management program and action plan related to the environmental impact by conducting ISO 14001:2015 internal audit.
 - Report the implementation of environmental management program result to management every three months.
 - Implement 5S & 7K, MBWA
 - Conduct training such Safety Dojo and hazardous waste handling
- Responsible for hazardous waste, waste water, and air pollution management implementation
 - Make sure the storage of hazardous waste to meet the criteria on government regulation.
 - Coordinate with licensed third parties for hazardous waste treatment
 - Make sure the waste water and air pollution meet the criteria of estate regulation
- Responsible to fulfill the PROPER requirements through online reporting system (SIRAJA & SIMPEL)
 - Report the monitoring and control of hazardous waste, waste water, and air pollution, also complete the technical
 aspects required.
- Responsible to make AMDAL document in form of RKL RPL Rinci based on Permenperin 1/2020.

Accomplishment

- Completed AMDAL Document (RKL RPL Rinci) update.
- Achieve BIRU rating in PROPER 2020 period.

GUNUNG RAJA PAKSI Tbk. | ENVIRONMENTAL STAFF

NOV 2018 - AUG 2019

Main Responsibilities

• Responsible to complete Environmental Permit Documents (AMDAL) requirements, analyse the technical aspects, analyse the environment test result (water, hazardous waste, emission, and ambient air) for Environmental Monitoring Document

(RKL-RPL Monitoring)

• Responsible to implement OHSAS 18001:2007 and ISO 14001:2015, make strategies and action plans, supervise and

internal audit to make sure the standards are implemented, make the report, and make corrective plan based on

management review.

• Responsible to propose the utilization of hazardous steel waste by reporting the study literature to management and

complete the SNI requirements.

Accomplishment

• Completed one of Environmental Permit Document and presented it to about 10 experts from Environmental Division

Bekasi Regency.

PANDAWA AGROTAMA KONTRUKSINDO | ENVIRONMENTAL STAFF

AUG 2017 - JAN 2018

Main Responsibilities

• Responsible to evaluate solid waste management system based on Zero Waste Concept on PUPR Ministry Office which produces about 20 m³/day solid waste a day and make improvement by giving advices to treat the hazardous waste and

leachete that produce by solid waste.

Responsible to monitor and direct 13 workers at MRF to work based on SOP.

• Responsible to develop the standard for Zero Waste Concept implementation on resident scale.

Accomplishment

• Improved the Zero Waste implementation by recycling the water content of leachete to use as water spray in air pollution

CERTIFICATES

SMK3 AND OHSAS 18001: 2007 AWARENESS

JAN 2018

Able to identify hazard, make risk assessment (HIRAC), and having understanding to implement the core components of risk

management system.

ISO 9001: 2015 AND ISO 14001:2015 AWARENESS

JAN 2018

Able to make document control and recording in quality management system and environmental management system, also having understanding to implement the core components of quality and environmental management system.

From JobStreet.com

ORGANIZATIONS

TECHNIQUE INFORMAL SCHOOL ORGANIZATION | HUMAN EMPOWERMENT DIVISION 2014-2015

Encouraged and taught 12 scavengers at Karang Pola Village making valuable handicraft that can be sold.

CIVIL STUDENT ORGANIZATION | SECRETARIAL DIVISION 2013-2014

Managed schedule for 4 main organization events that is participated by others division.

SKILLS

Professional Skills:

- Being familiar with Environmental Regulations (including the new regulation PP 22/2021)
- Mastering ISO 14001:2015 & ISO 45001:2018
- Mastering Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power point, Visio) and Autocad
- Mastering environmental online reporting system operation. (SIRAJA & SIMPEL)

Language Proficiency:

- Excellent reading and writing ability, good listening and speaking ability.
- TOEFL 513 points.